Yesterday, one of the most scandalous lawsuits in tech was revealed to the world.
An AI hardware company named IO is suing another AI hardware company named IO.
The former is a Google Back startup you've never heard of, while the latter is Johnny
Ives mysterious company that was acquired last week by OpenAI for a staggering $6.5 billion.
On the surface, it looks like a battle between IO and IO, but in reality, it's a proxy war
between OpenAI and Google.
If you're confused already, it all refers to the original company as IO,
and the company accused of stealing their name in IP as Altman IO.
You see, Sam Altman thought he was playing 70 chess by throwing helicopter money
at the legendary Sir Johnny Ives, a guy who is considered one of the most powerful people at Apple
who gave products like the iPod, Iphone, and MacBook their visual identity.
But this opening move just put the brand's future in jeopardy because now Altman IO is being
sued for trademark infringement, and if we're to believe this startup, the allegations are absolutely
unhinged. In today's video, we'll break it all down and take a look at the future AI hardware
that nobody asked for. It is June 24, 2025, and you're watching the code report.
If you've been following the AI race, you may know that Sam Altman made a massive deal to acquire
and hire Johnny Ives before an ungodly amount of money. As of right now, the deal is still on,
and Johnny will still get that bag. But before even revealing an initial product,
the brand might need to pivot because it's being sued by a Google Back startup called IO.
They've got 62 million in funding, a registered trademark, and 20,000 units ready to ship.
But what even is it? On the website, it's a quote, revolutionary new computer that doesn't need a
screen. You can run apps by simply speaking to it. Now, I don't mean to be a downer, but so far,
it seems like people don't want devices like this. Rabbit and Humane Pinn already tried similar
concepts and failed miserably. Maybe this startup will get it right, but enter Sam Altman and
Johnny Ives, who just announced their collaboration to build mysterious voice controlled AI devices.
They also called their product IO, and we don't know anything about it, but we can infer some
additional details about it from the lawsuit, and this is where things get wild. In 2022,
Sam Altman's investment fund met with IO. It got their tech demos, but said no thank you.
In addition, around the same time, Johnny Ives company also met with IO and saw their tech demos
and said no thank you. Behind the scenes, though, Altman and Ives were keeping tabs on IO,
while allegedly buying their products and asking for design files. Then a few years later in 2025,
OpenAI executive is met with IO. Once again, under the pretense of making an investment,
they were shown the tech, the hardware, and the functionality, but once again said no thank you,
were building our own slot. Then just weeks later, OpenAI released this cringe video,
vaguely hinting at some future hardware product. What's crazy, though, is that Altman not only
refused to make an investment in this startup, but incredibly he threatened that IO would sue IO to
force IO to stop using the name IO. These allegations are ruthless, salacious, and outrageous,
but that's what we've come to expect from Sam Altman. Unfortunately, it also puts a dark stain
on the clean reputation of Johnny Ives, who allegedly participated in this devious plot.
Only time will tell if they get to keep the name IO, but may the best hardware win.
When it comes to software development, though, we already have amazing tools, like Warp,
the sponsor of today's video. You probably know Warp for being the most intelligent terminal in the
game. And with their brand new 2.0 release, it's starting to rival the biggest AI dev tools out there.
You can now think of Warp as an agentic development environment. It comes with a state-of-the-art
coding agent that can execute jobs autonomously, a code editor where you can write code alongside
your agents, and an intelligent terminal, all in one. This means you can just tell Warp to build a
specific feature or fix a bug, and it can do it all with multiple agents in parallel. It scored
an impressive 71% on the SWE bench and 52% on terminal bench, which makes it one of the best
among agent-based dev tools. Warp is free to use, but you can get two months free on their
pro plan and a bunch of AI credits if you're one of the first 3,000 people to use the code
fireship at checkout. This has been the code report. Thanks for watching, and I will see you in the
next one.